Hello, what I want hello welcome before we get started please
squeeze in everyone this a full session people still coming in there's room here...the front and in the middle as
...should be room for everyone people ledges watson?
We got some seats up here in the middle...you can squeeze in all right let's start
...timer...time well yes hello andwelcome everyone to modern web
tooling in visual studio twenty fifteen.
...to build some websites...website.
And, there's a very big thing right here so.
Hello,...
That's because...not falling off the state here so,
my name is mass christensen and I work on the visual studio web tooling team-building all the acinet
and front-end development features in visual studio...look at some of
the new stuff that we have in twenty fifteen
so some of it you probably already seen if you've played around with the preview and
https but we have some new stuff and in the rc
build so hence of real quick how many here have installed the rc.
Okay,
that's good how many here have install the preview...one of the cpc has gone.
Ok, that's a that's a lot of you that's like half of the room that's also ok.
So, let's just look at.
So, what to talk about today is overflowing to build is going to the website
...do that with
the some of the new tooling on top of the new brand-new project system that drives asp
...five we will do a static website though so there's a lot of
eight-minute five...one more morning with damian and handsome so,
you definitely want to go check that one out but we're going to talk more about theso,
the tooling around it but not necessarily...
So, we have some new stuff for package managers that's really exciting we got some new task
runners that's...visual studio so you might have seen that.
we have some extensions and I'm just going to use them throughout these are extensions
...to do that of course...free and that you cannot live without or maybe I can
...by the more accurate also
bootstrap and angular and we'll see what happens but so,
let's start with beginning so package manager.
We are shipping a few new ones so the first one is our so
our is a client-side package manager let's say that you want.
J query angular js bootstraps
...client-side framework a library.
Our canal help you up so instead of using new get which we still
...you might want to start to look at our and there's a very good reason for this.
Sort of the rest of the world people not using visual studio new get.
They all use our so there's a huge
ecosystem around our and all the packages that are there all, you know,
when angular for instance just as example when
...new version of angular js they release it
to bauer they don't necessarily releases to...get so...have a lot more
up-to-date packages and a lot more of them on our which is really good?
So, bauer we're going...use that for client-side
packages so I'll tell that we also looking at a few task runner share.
And, specifically grunts and gulp.
Minute fining javascript and css falls bundling compiling
type script compiling coffee script into javascript so on
we can use sort-of industry-standard task...
So, we format of used...task amount of used
where essentials we might have used any other sort of tool or runtime
...and eight-minute runtime thing but, we can do now if we can do
...we can use it both at design-time in visual studio or on our build
...see ci...so on using grunt
...take a look at that and why that is a really, really good idea to do?
And,...finally the last package manager and...this is
...package manager.
So, we use that like rule of thumb that's how we bring
in tooling into our workflow.
So, that's how we bring in the task runners gulp
and grunt for instance we install them through the node package managers what really cool about this
as we can now version the tooling the compilers all the stuff that we do to build
...client-side application we
can version that per project.
So, you can update how your compiler, you know,
...compiler one project without it affecting another project
so you can always say up to the latest on your new project but you might want to keep to of performer
worse version on some other projects that you've got so that is now possible and if you think about what we're doing with
sp dot net five...the course...where you can version your
Internet application by shipping the runtime in the app itself.
Now you can do that with tooling as well as we can be...loop so that's really...
You also use and pm for client-side packages and that's fine too but, you know,
rule of thumb
...I look at that might be through in visual studio you want to use that for bringing...
The goals here.
For the ...in these tools.
...managers and task runners.
See this works rule is that they have to be first-class
citizens these are command-line tools they don't have any ui.
People that are not using visual studio maybe and the
...these tools for years they use them through the command-line.
So, we have to make sure that a visual studio understands
and supports these new tools it has to be as a first-class...right so we have to have the
we have solution explore integration we have a new tool window called task runner explore and
it just have to fill natural that is super important like the muscle memory that we all
have from using visual through the way that we experience visual studio
has to be the say by using these new command-line tools.
And, it's very important there's nothing
visual studio specific about it because the goal here is that.
Let's say you have a team and one person is on
windows in visual studio another team members on mac
...sublime text so first of all...five you can you can do that...
cross-platform but we want...the same...tooling and so.
If someone on
...sits on the command-line and performs all the same things for packets management and for task
werner's we...make sure that also works in visual through...and visual three doesn't add
anything that only works in visual studio has to work across-the-board.
Super important and this is apply like if we couldn't do this
we would not have implement any of the stuff that was like super important.
And, there is extensible so I mentioned the to
...got golden grunt.
This is expendable you can add providers for other stuff.
So, if you into...cs there's a pbs build system there's
a our shell one as well there's other type stuff you can this...you can add all this stuff yourself.
And, finally it's optional again very important if you don't want to use this.
But, I'm sure after today you all want to uses.
So, when...visual...those of you are
...the rc bits?
You notice that when the installer shows up and you have the list of check boxes which ones you want to
check right which...the features...install only one check box was
checked by default that was the web development tools
...everywhere and it's now sort of the base for a lot of different things like
...patch put...and all this stuff so that's the only one that's check
by default I assume since you're here in this room that you all...install that but,
when you do here's what you get in the box that you probably didn't?
Under the covers is not install globally
...living within visual studio somewhere undersea program file systems that.
You get the grunt see alive you want to use the grunt task burner.
And, you get so what this means is.
That visual studio
is able to work with all these tools which are all based on note js.
Without you having to install anything you don't actually even have to know that runs on oj
it doesn't matter happens in the background and this...able to handle that force.
Now if you want a new version of note x you want to new version of our like
an update comes up you can make sure the visual through takes the one that
version you want instead of taking the one that's...install by
...you're completely in control of what versions of each of these components the visual
...use which is really cool.
The question is does it added to the path.
So, the global environment variable...path does...added there's...consul and,
interact with these things no it doesn't we're looking at maybe doing that...but it doesn't do
...for various different reasons if you have some of them install already we don't
want have any the conflict there but, that might change?
But, as I will show you in a second that don't worry about that okay.
Here I have a really, really empty project is a new
...five project system.
And, it is very empty I don't know if you've probably seen this.
Keynote or some other presentation we have a new concept called the
...uproot is where we put our
static content like images style sheets so on what you might not know?
If we open project jason is
...configured...you can name...whatever you want.
To encode public
...or anything you want or you just a dot.
And, now the icon went away from over here I can delete this folder.
And, now the root of my project is...up root ok.
So, this is just for simplicity for the demo here we don't have a very empty.
Project so.
Let's just add a.
Index html so how do you do that you do like...click and say
add new item when you search for html.
Given name that's one way of doing.
It also just hit shift of...
And, do index html?
And, then we can do html five.
Boom like this right so.
This extension called add new file.
...not very creative with my naming of extensions
but this is one of the once you cannot live without.
Okay,
so, let's just put in some content let's do...header within each one.
And,...it.
So, now we have a beautiful beginning of a works under.
I want...rep.
So, what I would do before?
Is that I would use new get to bring in...this users framework
but in this new world I want use balance that okay and
to do that just like for...packages we have a file...packages to dot conflict?
Our has a very similar thing called our dot json.
So, let's just add a file to the root of...project called our...json.
So, here's what it looks like.
Just...file.
Check this out get full intel's sets.
And, we even get like the name here is at the top because it's a required property so that
makes it easy...this and let's write dependencies.
And, check this out bootstrap you get full intelligent from the bootstrap registry
online.
This is now search u search within intelligence here this is live search
result coming back frombauer.
And, we get the version number here and all I
have to do to install this package is to save this file.
Save here we go and we can now see
...manager does something here in.
The consul.
And, we now have a dependencies node same our
bootstrap and if we open...bootstrap depends on shakers...our takes care of our
dependencies just like negatives...also installed...
Now if we move over to.
What looks like on this we have a...components...
And, I have to trajectory right here it's flat lists.
So, this is nonstop we don't show that over here so the thing is what we can
...show hidden files folders we have our components...
So, I can now take the bootstrap that is in their.
Bootstraps users right it's in here under disks.
...about right here so I can just use that I can deploy my
our components...my web server and that's fine.
But, and,
you know, personally I like to just take the files that comes in through
bauer and copy them into a folder in my application so instead of shipping the entire
our components folder I just want to take only the fascinate and put them in my projects.
So, in order to do that I want that I want to automate that stuff so in case that
...update bootstrap one day I
...able to push a button and I get the first copies into my
project right so in order to do that I need to have some sort of task.
We've always had...as being sort of
...tasks runner of sorts and but, this new world we have other...like the
...gulp scenario this seems to be a better fit.
So, let's take a look at gulp.
So, first of all I need to install gulp.
And, goalis a note module...comes in through and pm?
...pm and bauer are very similar.
So, I'm going to file.
Call package dot json.
And,...very much the same.
Let's see here.
Again, name.
It doesn't matter what...
Version this was given this.
And, notice by the way down here so web essentials gives us a little icon here because I don't
know if you've noticed but this file and the our file.
Kind of look the same.
But, all these
...following so web essentials puts in a little logo down here in the...so we can so we're...nice.
So, we do the same thing here
which adif dependencies let's get gulp.
And, let's get this version I'm just going to...it and we see now the
...window here we see what's going to what happens under the covers.
And, for those of you use these tools on the command-line.
We're just calling in pm install.
Everything visual studio has done so far is acting as a proxy between
me and the command-line so I don't have to use the command-line if I want to.
We have our gulp so here and all the dependencies again
we don't show the actual node modules folder.
But, it is right here we see we have
...so now I have a specific version of
...installed in my specific project and I can...start using tasks.
Let's start doing that so I want
...file called gulp file that actually.
If you don't want all that you can you can still doat new item and,
... search for gulp and there is all this of...
And, the and pm so it's all here.
You can search for...like that extension think that's.
That's great so if I could do that.
...file the js.
And, it's empty right so if I had...add new item chose to go file it
would have been urban something in there but.
I have a snippet you have a snippet will have
...snippet pogo.
...tap and we're set up here so another
...tasks that copies my our components my bootstrap into my projects.
So, here's how that works.
We have some helpers and gulp notice here that you get really,
really nice intel's if I can hit the keyser you get really nice intelligence
check this up to make it really, really easy and we want the source.
Is usually what you always want because now we're going to point at?
The this is the...leisure so our.
Underscore components.
Bootstrap.
...so that's I remember the full disrupt you might not but I've done this before.
And, then we're going to pipe that so gulp is a screen based task managers
...streams now I'm going to create a file stream because
of your select these files on-disk I'm going to pipe that stream into.
In this case sort of the opposite
...place to put the file to save them as another file chemicals so...I have a
...desks so let's put this at the root of all the
...lip does not exist yet.
And,...bootstrap like this.
Going to save this file.
So, we have this new thing called task runner explore.
That shows up right here.
Just by me saving the file it goes out and figure out
...the tasks available and the copy test
I just created is available right here so I cannot just click it.
And, that was quick was a little too...
so covenant eight-point three-four milliseconds that's the speed of gulp
...so very faster so now I have everything
here I can go into my page let's at.
What we say...
Bootstrap...us-versus-them...one here.
Like that.
And, then we can...probably raptors in a container so for those of you familiar with bootstrapping
going to add some classes to our html to take advantage of that so we have well,
new little thing called the surround with
tag right it's just a little thing but it's so great.
Like that...do that again shift alt w so those you
...text, you know, the...the same so...
And, I'm just going to keep the...hit the space...
And, class equals work.
Close equals
...container notice...how you get the full intelligent showing up with the
icon here...is the bootstrap icon so we know that this is bootstrap.
And, this is called page header.
Let's just say this.
And, then we go back to.
So, now it looks a lot better right so now we have our responsive ui we've set up bootstrap
very simply but the cool thing is that might be you add a little bit of files
...the beginning but the way we can automate this from now on is really,
really powerful ok so now I have a full work for...
taking advantage of...pm our and gulp two-run tasks I
have not touch the command-line I have not out anything...say like it feels kind of
issues too like I don't know if you agree but there's nothing out-of-the-ordinary really.
I can take a step further.
I can have my any of my task to do something.
When a specific visual studio event occurs?
So, let's go back here to our copy
...right click I can bind that to
say after built.
Like that so now after build.
...copy...so what does that mean...means if I now built control shift b.
...migrant test or delta.
It's my muscle memory that I keep intact here and under the hood we
spin up node and do all sorts of fancy things but you don't notice and you don't have to nodes okay?
Okay.
That was part of it so let's look at bringing in angular.
Sometimes it's a little while to find the version here we go.
And, let's just say that and while that is installing into my dependencies.
Let's go to the goal file n.
Do something similar?
Angular.
This is a little different I want everything that
start with angular that has either js or map as
the file extension and I'm going to put that over here triangular.
Say that.
Execute my copy task.
And, I'll have angular.
...how you get this nice file nesting by default now.
All right so again we go back to our index pitcher and
scripts.
Into this.
So, install these paris when you first...is extremely fast and convenient.
There's obviously doesn't do anything yet because what I really want to do first...I want to add a
little custom styling so right now...just bootstrap the default sort of bootstrap theme.
But, I want to add a little custom.
Design basically so I want to use css
but actually a really want to use less instead of...a less for those
of you haven't tried that is sort of a superset of css that compiles down to...
Let me just that less file again.
Now take this up this...a folder call less
and inside that I want to add variables that less.
And, here we go.
Now have are less folder right
here with variables let's just do something really fantastic such as create a variable called background.
Tomato that's an actual color.
And, say that.
It's not because there's building...
So, let's add a new file a new less file.
...site godless.
So, here I just want to import.
My variables less right here.
And, we can do something as fancy as set the background color
...you get the...your flows in from my important variables file I can...
and says tomato so that's kinda nice so now I have my very beautiful layout
...all done and I want to compilers into
less so again there has been a lot of ways to
do this before use web essentials one-way
use some runtime component that's another way use...is build a third way.
But, we're is gulp and what really cool about this is that we can do
it all statically again because it's gulp it works on test servers
...works on ci servers and all this stuff we did not get that with representatives but if
...essential...the workflows broken so this case?
I'm just going to use gulp.
So, if we jump in here too.
Package jason...to get...compilers I'm actually
...the compiler into my project right now and that's this version going to save that.
And, it's now installing so if we look over here.
No.
It running godless it's coming in so now I just have to create a compile
test so gulp task so...essentials...a few extra
...snippet here looks like this.
Let's do some less compiling what I'm going to do here is again I'm going to find one of the files I
want to listen to...got watch I'm going to say.
...source.
To say find any file in the less folder that ends with
...so this is clotting patterns...really cool about this the flexibility we
get here in terms ofthe clotting patterns to find the files
...the files is amazing right we get that for free...used to our
...you know-how sort of the search patterns in the
...patterns work it's very similar to this.
And, it's really powerful...less file that exist in my less folder.
Pipe that well first of all forgot the most important
part I have to actually include.
My less compilers
...currently less equals require.
...get nice intelligence called less.
...pipe my less file.
Actually I'm only going to save my site...less because it
...my variables the list so piped my newly imported less component...
...that function not check this up I get intelligence
for the different options available for this specific less.
Compiler.
This is a new feature in two thousand fifteen we have what's
called object literal intel's so I'm inside anonymous object in...and object
little javascript and we can now have full intelligence so I can set this
to compress equals true which means minute
phi so if you're noticing what I'm doing here I have to less files
...imports the other one...
That's sort of bundling and then I'm compressing as well like...
very easily I can compile less do my bundling and modification.
And, I can do it all.
Like this gulp dot destination now I can put in any folder I
want but let's just let's just put in the exact same folder just because why not.
So,...floor you can see we now have our list tasks user was right.
Forty milliseconds.
And, I have site...us magnified and compiled right here.
So, this is really nice and I can hear to my variables and
...this to green and go back here and run the task again.
...done and now I get the ohm...follows updated want to...is please it's green.
So, that's really nice but, the workflow...not very good, you know, I don't want to
...manually run this task every time I want to have an automatically so,
let's just do that.
So, let's go back to images close to sites user let's go back here so what I want to do is
want to set of file watcher.
That listens to
whenever any less file in my less folder changes I wanted to recompile less.
Leisure do a goal test...watch.
And, here...to say any less file it doesn't matter which less file I'm going to modify.
I want to run one or more tasks in this case just one...less.
...so,...now see the...shows up
...say that.
Is now running?
As you can see here it's running
doesn't do anything it just watches my folder so.
Let's change the variable here to blue.
And, you can...you're really quickly it ran
we're talking milliseconds here it's really fast and we can see here now my output is
bloop so this is the work...want I want to automatically do this
...stuff when I save the file...make sense.
But, you know, do I have to then automatically start the watch task every...
Know because.
I can write click my watch task.
And,...to project open.
So, I think.
You can guess what happens when I...the project.
Will automatically startup actually...something that's even cooler than that?
Let's say that your node modules and your
bar components folders empty because you might not check into source control and you do a
...of fresh get latest or get clone or whatever you do and.
This will automatically restore your packages and then it will call the
watch task.
The idea is here that it's the same thing is when you use the command-line but.
But, just...let's stop this...task.
Let's open the...
All space.
Have another great extension?
Called open command-line.
I need a pr organism...so open command-line does.
Open commitment and it's whatever file your on here...open
sit at the that directory or if...specific directory you can say like open command-line
...I want the...command prompt our...or like just completely customize
is a well which one do you want to run...run commander or something custom whatever
...to your favoritepocket and all that stuff so that's really what that
comes in handy...reasons so one of them is that we can interact with...pm
and our and...but also if you want to run...tasks or the get commands
...commands...has a lot of multipurpose
there's let's just run gulp which is how...
So, this looks pretty much identical to what we saw in the
task unexplored on here when I ran that.
let's just say that you...fine with the command-line which a lot of people...that's cool.
You don't have to use the task explore.
You just do this and we see here if I change this back to.
Corn silk maybe.
And, save that.
Said my...this file was updated.
...go so how fast it was but now I'm running
...consul that runs submissions...because it's the same thing super important
is super important that is the same thing okay.
Thing here so that was called this.
...us right there.
And, now we have beautiful corn
silk which is like almost what was that was not a good what...dodger blue.
Ok, so, this thing is...right.
Close...
Okay, that's beautiful.
Let's go back to my index...so let's so,
...have angular I have my styling...for me to build my app.
Let's do that.
So, what we want to you want
creative want to create an input so basically I want to do like basic model
...angular so let's just do inputs with the class?
Equals.
Form control like this.
And, what so let's just see what that looks like that is very pretty but
what I really want to do is I want to have a little icon up...this...frameworks...come
with like icons that we can use like icon fonts I want to icon?
To show up
here so for that I'll have to give this a class equals.
Input group.
That...do a spam.
And, this span has a class...well called.
...that and then I'm ready to add my this is bootstrap this just
bootstrap witness rightbut, now I'm ready to inject my image.
So, let's just do and I it doesn't matter class.
Equals cliff icon not...it took this up.
Is...is that?
Works bootstrap.
Foundation.
...moon yes that is a thing.
And, find awesome yep and one more what is the...
five-thirty five more to come of course this is actually extension that is called this called
...friends.
...a list of all these extension afterwards but so,
a guy called...williams he wrote this and he figure out
there was actually issues with visual studio and how this would work so
he just contact us hey I can make this work the way I want to so we fix
that so for rc it's now possible to do what he does here and today he's releasing this thing
so that's really exciting that works for all these different libraries so we're going
to do something like a I think that briefcase would be appropriate...
So, let's use that.
So, my input here I'm going to do angular here so of course you get like nys icons
...angular, angular model tools
...I'm just mechanism text and.
Then let's do something to something out here maybe.
Nice syntax highlighting...them.
So, now I'm model binding.
My input box to that little...quote field right there and because...angular
we always remember to do this if we have to which we do in this case.
Now we go back.
And, I did on the wrong element so.
There's that.
Hello, world.
Slash build so now we have.
An angular app...it's simple...we get all this without having to use the command-line without
I'm doing this and I hope you kinda see the value of using these package
managers the our of using gulp or grunt
they sort of solve the same problems...case you're wondering why...gulp...
It...have been either or it's always a personal preference I prefer build myself
and this is not hard I hope that you agree this is not.
As scary maybe
...when I started looking into the as I was little bit scary is very simple
and the goal here is to close the gap between
the visual studio world and sort of the rest of the world.
So, you probably come across this issue where you go to a website
like you go to like some javascript library that you want to download
...the website and it says here download here just...our install.
And, you're like well I don't know what to do that information.
...and the same goes for like node
modules right so there has been well I'm a visual
studio person so this whole our install thing that doesn't apply to me so this is not for me let me just
go search new get and maybe you find a negate maybe so what we're trying to do here is to
close the gap and eliminate the whole like us and them.
Let's just all be happy to...use the same tools.
You want to sit on a...and sublime another key member
...in visual studio that's awesome just deployed...but, moi.
So, that but that's the our of all this stuff and what's cool about all
this stuff I just showed you a works in cordova apps as well
the grunt the got it works in nbc.
Five it works in, you know,...forms works in website projects all the, you know,
save the our file automatically...or installs these components
...it works everywhere I have projects running on both waveforms
And, website projects and...a web pages all using the same.
Tools that we see here.
And, have them build and ci servers...stuff so people ask me a lot like why did
why have I removed the less compilers and stuff like that from web essentials?
I don't know if you've noticed but, I have in the two thousand fifteen version.
Well, there are several reasons one was.
Current was not very stable so the crashes
...came from those components in...also that it
didn't have the flexibility that we have here like the way I can do the
swapping patterns to find out the exact files reckoned
...between the different functionality they bring in
...essentials cannot do that you need something richer more like programming or like javascript.
And, the third of all.
I can't compile web essentials
anymore with the huge number of the node modules that we include inside
...essentials so that's why it's gone.
...and I think I hope you agree that this
isn't okay substitute this is really powerful stuff.
And, finally it works nci that was the big...or from pptx
...from the so from get help to deployed to windows to as a...so on.
But, there's one more thing.
When is the task miracles let's just...a click the copy
...done it kills it director if I watch
for a file it never ends here I'm just watching it running
...keeps running...does not di articulate?
...visual studio precious.
No, the process goes with it so no you're not going to have lingering project processes running because of this.
Let's just look at ...install react.
...here looking at react js bring around with it being
frustrated on visual studio while trying to do that.
So, I'm just going to say my bauer that means that shows up in the meanwhile going to
...in here and copied over so
...this other framework javascript framework...josephine works.
Anything starting with...called js.
React save that.
...that from the copy.
...we have react.
Anything that you add any javascript framework that you at what we want
to remember is a bit unfortunate but we always have to remember this?
Weird file called underscore references the js.
Okay, you've seen it and thought what the hell is that.
I'll show you so.
Underscore refer...the js.
It's a file that we need for intel's sense to pick up all the
different javascript...we...approach we need it because we want
intelligence for maybe every javascript...project are only a few of them.
So, we list here what is that we want in the order that we
want because remember the javascript errors in visual studio is the only one of
its kind that actually executes javascript.
To ordering matters it's like in the browser you have to load j query before any
...query plugins right same thing goes here so but,
you know, it's kind of easy so I just have my reference js I can write click
an solution explore or I can write click...in here.
...update javascript references organs...that means whenever I
...or delete javascript file just automatically shows up in your or is being removed
so update javascript references gives me this I don't necessarily want
michael file in this case and maybe I want references to be up here so alt
...is up and down?
To move lines of...
That's pretty good so just
...we used to have a rule that the
underscore references...had to be in a folder called scripts.
If you're like me you don't necessarily like a full called scripts.
I prefer one called js whatever and now you can put...
Will just find the...
And, let's add a we actuators file so.
The highest requested feature of the most requested feature
of in visual studio for anything web related...support for reactor.
Believe it up and it's because
reactor is very unique what they do is that they are creating an extension
on top of javascript yes yet another extension on-topic javascript and they call
js x for xml I guess it's basically putting
sort of xml literals into javascript or in
our case html.
this is sort of the reversed world like we have an html page with a script tag and we put javascript in there,
you know,...for years this is sort of the opposite we have a javascript file
we just put inline html into.
Neither a similar or the javascript answer liked that...visual studio.
Let's just create a...let's create alerts the ds x.
And, so.
We get this so far so good.
What we did was we...that to facebook which are the
...to build and maintain react js and ask them how we're going to implement this in the
best way and they've got...help us and the together we've come up with?
I would say like a pretty awesome way of doing it now what you have an rc is the
first-time we ship it but it wasn't in any of the...
Because there's a lot of initial work we had to do before we could start adding
...the polishing the features so it's a very on polished editor
is not perfect it is only the beginning and actually
I have open the file like this before but the first-time you open a js...you'll get a nice
dialog boxes...hey this is very new
...on it just
fyi know that might be a few things.
we can others of like a var alert equals.
React dot.
Logic this up you get like nice until
...create class like.
All this stuff comes out here.
So, create class.
And, ...just...tab.
So, here we see we have you can see the colonization of my
...right here inside javascript we do have a little reads quickly.
This is one of those things...just ignored
...rc I...have picked already but it didn't make it into the...
As you saw earlier I had an issue with getting.
Class equals its that...name...that's because I've been playing around with some of
this stuff right here because in js x we cannot use the name
class because that's a reserved keyword in javascript so we do classmate.
So, that's.
Exactly how that worked and so.
This props.
Dot message that.
So, this is now I'm creating and angular closer component so now I can say
...rc again a snippet.
...notes.
So, here...kind of data points
to this props for properties that message which we haven't defined anywhere we don't really have to.
Message equals hello.
Build.
the purpose of having the...in rc the reason why we really wanted out there for you guys
...is because even though we know it's a little rocky.
Is because we wanted to make sure that we can on blockers...for those of you tried it and
Got angry that
didn't work and you got like weird experience before you are now on blocked to work on
js x but I can promise you it's going to be so good when we're done with visual...twenty fifty?
So, this is a...x again we use gulp to.
To compile into javascript.
Okay, so, a few things...
what you might have noticed is that we have...popping up
in a few at new places so one of them is.
In json files.
We get intelligence here that's one place.
Another place that you saw.
Was inside.
Let's take our goal file her gulp dot something this is
...js right this is not just this is not a javascript thing
...this file is being executed by...
But, this is the javascript editor so how do we get intelligence well.
If we look at the answer we can
...top of any of these vassar schema store dot org.
Which you might not have heard about?
So, this is schemas dot org open-source community run websites
website here that has some stuff for...for javascript she says it's on
its way html make it up here and some point what's really cool here is that visual
studio to...fifteen rc has built-in support for jason's
and connection to the schema store dot org repository of these
forty-one files so that means not only can you create in
...and validation for your own custom jason formats.
But, you can add it to schema...and everyone will get it and
you can paired up with files file names so we know that when we open afar called our
jason.
Schema store tells us that if your profile
...jason this is the url to the schema of that file and if you
...request...this website.
Will show up in everyone's visual studio automatically if I take the
Which I probably...
But, this is how we drive all the project jason's...at five...lot of the...com
...there's php and chrome extension schemas here but drives insource so now you can actually
write extensions to visual...without writing and extension.
So, we received a lot of this coming in the
future where we centralize a lot of this stuff so that we can...
are abandoned everyone can participate that goes with javascript to so this is a little bit newer
so there's not that much but you saw how intel's insurer for react
forgot file that's all here that's java these
files javascript you can add intelligence in here.
And, visual studio in this case for now short-term what essentials
will bring in these files and intel's just gets better.
It's simply just gets better you don't have to
do anything except installing essentials which you all will.
that's really cool so I'm really happy that we're going to do this receives as well.
...do for html so all the schema files we have in visual studio we're going
to open-source that we're going to put it up on schema
store for everyone to helpmodify and
update to the latest browser standards and wthree-c and blah-blah-blah
we can now all do that it's all on get help is all static website really easy
...contribute to so I'm really happy about that we can start open
sourcing a lot of what drives the web tooling
...figure...see a lot more that coming.
Here's a here's...works.
And, the extensions that I was showing.
Are all freely available but essentials of course the
...new file open command-line great names different that is the one that is the one that
had the bootstrap icons all that all that fun awesome and foundational react snippet
...for those run want around that what I didn't get to show was image
...and multi editing feel free to get take a picture of this so it's all
about visual studio gallery dot com images search for these names?
Image optimize are...I...extension...image optimize
...for years and build that into.
What essentials the old image optimized extension stop working?
It was calling some service that didn't exist anymore and now I've ported
...web...back into the all image optimize are removed from
...breaking things up a little bit so you definitely want that and improve that...comprises even better now
whether multi editing really, really cool...just-released last week for two thousand fifteen this is the one
...you...multi carrots multicore support...
I'm not sure what this...we got a few
a minutes left for question so just raise your hand sequence I'll repeated so everyone can hear.
Notice install by business through yet.
How do you up yes so how do we update the things that...also...node check this up?
We can just go to.
Tools options...I'm doing tools options.
And, where is that thing external web tools?
And, we can decide what
path we want first so what I've done is I'm using my own versions of
note this because might global path is before the visual studio path like
the default restore default is that we look in the visual studio first.
So, you can just you could delete these...once and you're in control.
Yeah, you...complete control.
Is there syrian support there's there are node modules I can
use through gulp that will make that very easy if you're using is put on that five we now have really,
really cool tag helpers that has the native cd including fallback
support so let's say the...down...locally I really, really awesome stuff?
Yeah, it's an easy way to update packages such as a new...about packages.
List them...
Yes, no, you cannot super-power you cannot see what packages are have an update ready
for you this is something we're looking at for an update potentially but,
you can just open our...and safer file.
Literally update things...yes.
How did hit so
now that we're using so the question is something like this now that we're using node under the covers a
...node modules folder how we're going to...long paths issue?
If you don't check identity fs which I would not do that personally some people think it's
...don't then that's an issue...just say you solve...for achievers by not check into that because
...were like new...you don't chicken-and-egg pages either.
Which brings me to another extension that I didn't even talk about?
It's calledbecause what we want to do so node is a hierarchy so inside node
modules...gulp...that that's a full called node modules...has other node modules that has other node
modules and long path exception...
What...do is one of flapping the packages so we don't have these deep hierarchies and you can do that
their stuff out there will help you or we can just rightly node modules and click flatten packages?
And, it asks.
So, runs so this again free extension I have a thing with naming
this extension withhold...packages.
...runs...this is note that runs and dusters some note doesn't
have an issue with long path right so it's note...executes this that's why it works.
...the...so...html five or javascript base the windows apps yes you can use
bauer gulp all of that stuff in the beginning you won't see the solution explore
the dependency note you won't see that show up but you get I give you add
...save it will restore the packages you can use gulp that that's all the same
...explore works all that...for any project if you want to
...consulate works to...why would you.
Sorry I'm out of time please come up fword thank you very
much the one-third left.
Thank you.
And, remembered so...place.